<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/medablog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/medablog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-22T23:09:05-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/medablog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Medablog</title><subtitle>A blog dedicated to Medabots news and fan projects!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">New Medawatch, who dis?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/medablog/medabots/2021/07/22/New-Medawatch-Who-Dis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Medawatch, who dis?" /><published>2021-07-22T21:17:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-22T21:17:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/medablog/medabots/2021/07/22/New-Medawatch-Who-Dis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/medablog/medabots/2021/07/22/New-Medawatch-Who-Dis.html">&lt;p&gt;Heyo, Variant here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always kinda wanted to live that hip blogger life and figured with the power of GitHub Pages and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, it was finally time. It’s a little empty right now, but make yourselves at home :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal is to keep people updated on the status of the Medabots Game Boy and Game Boy Color translation projects &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Medabots&quot;&gt;we’re working on&lt;/a&gt;, as well as what we might be stuck on…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We might also have some posts regarding Medabots news in general if I can convince some people to contribute here, so keep your fingers crossed for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for a status update, here’s what we’ve got…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;medabots-1-game-boy&quot;&gt;Medabots 1 (Game Boy)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The patch is out there and playable (get the latest patch &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Medabots/medarot1/releases/latest&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The portraits version is still in-progress, I’d love to find someone who’s played the WonderSwan version and could help map the portraits accordingly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/OnionBoy0&quot;&gt;Someone&lt;/a&gt; has been working on the Spanish translation of the patch, I’m pretty sure it’s close to completion if not completed already
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;He’s also been working on doing portrait mapping and trying to add the Medabots lines that don’t exist at all in the GB version (though, without sprites)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;parts-collector-12&quot;&gt;Parts Collector 1/2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Text is dumped, and it’s pretty much identical to Medarot 1 code-wise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We need a translator
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I think there’s only a few hundred lines total, and most are duped between the two games&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;medabots-3&quot;&gt;Medabots 3&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Text is dumped (about 7500ish unique lines)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We need translators (and probably someone to drive localization)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you leave localization to me, we’ll see a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://medabots.github.io/medarot3_dialog-previewer-js/index.html?t=%3C@LL,02,00%3EThe%20streets%20ain%27t%20ready%20for%3CD3%3Ethis.%0A%3C@RR,00,06%3EHoly%20Meda-roli!%3C*04%3E&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We have some translators who drop-in from time to time, but no huge driven effort to get everything translated :(&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disassembly/hacking work is in-progress to translate tilemaps
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Though, we kinda need translators for some things&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;site--blog&quot;&gt;Site / Blog&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Right now the site is &lt;a href=&quot;https://medabots.github.io&quot;&gt;empty&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ideally I’d like to use it to link to relevant wikis and project pages at some point&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m not particularly gifted at making things look pretty, maybe someone wants to volunteer to spruce up the main page and blog?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all I’ve got for now. Maybe we’ll have found a translator by the next time I post.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Variant</name></author><category term="medabots" /><summary type="html">Heyo, Variant here.</summary></entry></feed>